# Javier García Salcedo

♣ Philosopher | Logician | Full-Stack Developer

**J** (52) 5555088893

ightharpoonup jagasal@icloud.com

in javiergss

## Professional Profile

I am a philosopher and a logician graduated from the National Autonomous University of Mexico and the University of Toulouse II, and a natural communicator. I've worked in academia for 15+ years and successfully instilled my passion for mathematical logic and the humanities in a great many of my students. Recently, I have obtained my MIT/xPRO professional certificate in full-stack development with MERN, and I am presently pursuing new professional paths as a front- and back-end developer.

## Work Experience

Modern American School Aug 2015 - Present: Logic and Philosophy Professor I deliver courses on logic, ethics and history of philosophy. I provide my students with the analytical skills and conceptual resources for them to develop a unique and robust interpretation of themselves and their place in the contemporary world.

Technological Autonomous Institute of Mexico Aug 2011 - May 2020: Assistant Professor I delivered the courses of Modern and Contemporary Western History and Philosophy, as well as Political and Economic Issues of Contemporary Western Civilization. I instilled in my students a deeper appreciation of the relevance of philosophy to their technical and professional activities. I advised several undergraduate theses in applied mathematics and law.

National Autonomous University of Mexico Aug 2010 - June 2019: Assistant Professor I imparted courses on the philosophy of mathematics, many-valued logics, propositional and first-order logic, propositional and first-order modal logic, set theory and the meta-theory of propositional and first-order logic. I and other colleagues organized the Ist National Conference in the Philosophy and History of Logic and Mathematics held in February 2015, which brought together some of the most important names in the field and provided new generations of researchers a platform to showcase their work. I coordinated several seminars, and advised logic and philosophy undergraduate and graduate theses.

Elena Poniatowska's Archives Jan 2006 - June 2007: Research Assistant I coordinated the team conducting the journalistic research that underpins Elena Poniatowska's "Amanecer en el Zócalo. Los 50 días que confrontaron a México" (Planeta, 2007).

Entropía Humana S.C. Jan 2003 - Sept 2005: Cultural Manager I was in charge of managing the company's musical portfolio.

¡Río Loco! Festival Sept 2002 - July 2004: Artistic Advisor I appraised the work of international musicians and assessed their relevance to the festival definitive line-up.

Canal Sud Radio 92.2 FM Nov 2002 - Jan 2003: Radio Producer, Host and DJ I was charged with the musical curatorship of the show 'Catemaco' and the research for its news segment. I was also a host of the show.

#### **Education**

National Autonomous University of Mexico 2003 - 2007: Master in Philosophy and Logic Thesis title: "Wittgenstein's notion of Linguistic Understanding". Thesis advisor: Salma Saab, PhD.

University of Toulouse II

2000 - 2002: Master in Philosophy of Language

Thesis title: "Form and Usage in Wittgenstein's Philosophy". Thesis advisor: Xavier Verley, PhD.

University of Toulouse II

1997 - 2000: Bachelor's Degree (Major: Philosophy)

Lycée Français Louis Pasteur

1981 - 1996: *High School Degree* 

### ⟨**/>** Technical Skills

✓ MERN stack

✓ React.js

**✓** MongoDB

✓ JavaScript

✓ Node.js ✓ Strapi

✓ Express.js

✓ HTML5

✓ GitHub

✓ Stripe ✓ Logical analysis

✓ CSS3

✓ Docker

**✓** Swagger

**✓** DigitalOcean

✓ Formal semantics

### **\*** Certifications

- # Full-Stack Development with MERN (MIT/xPRO, 2023)
- \* Project-Based Learning (UNAM, 2022)
- \* Sixty years of AI (UNAM, 2022)
- \* Certificate in Logic (UNAM, 2004)

#### At Languages

- **③** Spanish Native
- French Bilingual Proficiency
- **\Pi** English Bilingual Proficiency
- Portuguese Professional Working Proficiency

### Published Papers

- Review of "The Writer's Workshop: Imitating Your Way to Better Writing", by G. Roper, in *Estudios*, ITAM, Mexico City, 116, 2016.
- "La escalera de Wittgenstein", in Estudios, ITAM, Mexico City, 112, 2015.
- Translation into Spanish of the article "Scepticisme Cartésien et Scepticisme Huméen", by Pascal Engel, in *Dudas filosóficas. Ensayos sobre escepticismo antiguo, moderno y contemporáneo*, A. Cíntora y J. Ornelas (eds.), Gedisa/UAM, Mexico City, 2014.
- Review of Bertrand Russell y al análisis filosófico a partir de "On Denoting", by Silvio Pinto (ed.), in Crítica, UNAM, Mexico City, 42-126, 2014.
- "La question du silence dans le Tractatus", in Les Cahiers d'Adèle, Toulouse,1, 2008.
- "Atribución de creencias justificativas para una predicción con reservas", in *Ergo*, University of Veracruz, Xalapa,19, 2006.